

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211





Kiran Onapakala Kiran Onapakala 🙆 Featured 🥛 Team Lead seeking roles in Application Design, Application Development, Project Management, Client Relationship Management, Requirement Gathering, Business Analysis, Process Management, Cloud Computing, Quality Assurance, C#, VB . Net, XML Current Designation: Team Lead & Application SQL Total Experience: 9 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Developer Notice Period: 1 Month Current Company: American Legal Net India Pvt. Ltd Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electrical] Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Pref. Location: Hyderabad, Other International Location Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Maintenance Role: Team Lead/Tech Lead Industry: IT-Software/Software Services Marital Status: Married

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Management, Cloud Computing, Quality Assurance, C#, VB . Net, XML

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

A technocrat with 9 years of multi-facet experience in Application Development, Cloud Computing (Microsoft Azure & AWS) and as Scrum Master

Key Skills: Team Lead & Scrum Master, Team Lead/Tech Lead, Application Design, Application Development, Project

Management, Client Relationship Management, Requirement Gathering, Business Analysis, Process

Experienced in managing Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC) using Agile/Scrum Methodologies including requirement analysis, design, testing & maintenance phases

Resourceful in managing IT Projects using Scrum Methodologies encompassing design, resource administration, process management and compliance with quality standards

Proficient in Business Analysis processes, & workflow to design solutions (As-Is, To-Be, and Solutioning/Freezing), and preparing requirement & testing documents (BRDs, PRDs & FDDs)

Recognized as Best Performer of the Year 2017 for server's migration to cloud in Nike Inc.

Work Experience

• American Legal Net India Pvt. Ltd as Team Lead & Application SQL Developer Jul 2018 to Till Date

Project/Client: eFiling Application (https://www.efilingportal.com/)

Domain: Legal firms

Description: American Legal Net provides software which is accurate, easy to use & rule-based docketing and calendaring software for law firms (Major clients: Skadden, ALSTON & BIRD, Morrison Foerster). It has connections with US Court, Agency, Attorneys and Legal Firms. It also maintains the docketing system for reminders, court data & documents.

Responsibilities:

Gathering the requirements from client and implementing the functionalities as per the legal standards

Collaborating with Customers and Product Manager to prioritize and validate requirements

Executing plans for long-term goals using Microsoft Project

Coordinating the work efforts of 14-Person Team for various projects; assisting team to complete tasks successfully & on-time and resolving obstacles encountered by team members

Coordinating & participating in weekly estimation meetings to provide high-level estimate (story points) for backlog items

Administering multiple projects CRMT (Court Rules Management Tool) & eDockets web application to manage dynamic requests

Integrating the data between CRMT and eDockets web applications

Preparing & modifying the SSRS reports as per the client requirements

Developing Web API Service to communicate with Auto Document System & Email Exchange

Creating XML Web Services for application to retrieve costing information

Using JQuery & JavaScript to validate all the User Inputs for interactive ASPX pages

Environment: SQL 2017, SSRS/SSIS, C#, ASP.Net, ASP.Net M/C, VS 2017, Bitbucket, Web API, AngularJS, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, JQuery, LINQ, ADO.Net entity framework, Agile Methodology, Jira Software, Source Tree, Bitbucket, DevOps

1

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Vedhas Technology Solutions Pvt. Ltd as Senior Software Developer Jun 2016 to Jul 2018

Project: Envision (https://www.envisionoverseas.com/)

Domain: Educational Services

Description: Envision is a dynamic web application which guides students after their primary school. This contains dashboards for the parents regarding their kids' activity. It also includes the messaging system where every student has access to write essays & other competition related topics and send to coaches. Coaches will assess those essays and write back to students.

Responsibilities:

Facilitated improvement in team delivery commitments & capacity planning for sprints by identifying & tracking hidden tasks that increased customer satisfaction

Ensured Agile Adoption Retrospective for the organization with the leadership and guided teams with outcome resulting in enhanced performance

Collaborated with client's team on project to implement Entity Data Access Layer (DAL), Business Logic Layer (BLL), Model-View-Controller (MMC), User Controls and Custom Controls

Worked in Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) environment and developed CSR applications with MVC comprising Analysis, Design, Implementation and Testing

Exchanged data from database, used ADO.Net objects and developed LINQ Queries

Used Asynchronous Calling of JSON, ¡Query & AJAX to implement validations for all Input Controls

Utilized ¡Query to load data from controller to view

Implemented various state management techniques to manage Sessions and Query Strings

Debugged applications with Visual Studio .Net Debugger and Trace Functionality

Consumed Web API to store product data in SQL Server Tables

Created tables, joins, functions, views, constraints & triggers in Mcrosoft SQL Server 2017; liaised with team to design and implement module level unit test cases

 $\overset{\circ}{\text{Contributed}}\text{ in Smoke Testing to ensure different integration points of the system and key business functionality met requisites}$

Environment: C#, ASP.NET 4.5, Visual Studio 2015, ASP.Net core 2.0, ASP.NET MC 5, ADO.NET Entity
Framework,
HTTPS LINQ, SQL Server 2017, jQuery, AJAX, XML, HTML5 & CSS 3, JavaScript, WEB API, IIS 7.0,
Protocol, Windows 2007, GITHub, Jenkins

HireITPeople LLC as Senior .Net Developer

Apr 2015 to Apr 2016

Project/Client: Nike Inc. (Retail https://www.nike.com), Beaverton, OR, USA

Domain: Product based

Description: Global Store System (GSS) includes various applications including Point of Sale & Inventory Management. The Point of Sale System had a Register Application that was used by store cashier to perform customer transactions at store check-out, and a back-office application that helps manage the start of day, end of day and cash management activities related to store operations.

Responsibilities:

Headed Application Engineering Team to fix all point of sale software issues and customized applications running for the client

Collaborated with vendor to provide & report any issue during store operations

Contributed as a part of Level-3 Support Team to define production support strategy & resolve production issues

Developed multiple automation tools to avoid any issues in daily store operations

Defined release strategy for maintenance releases to Global Nike Stores and Corporate Servers

Coordinated with various Business Units, Development Team, Quality Assurance Team, Operations Group and Change Management Team to plan, manage, and implement production releases

Administered 24*7 On-Call support for store solutions across global locations

Assisted Project Manager, created a comprehensive set of non-functional & functional requirements, and established processes to improve operations by automation, better reporting & metrics

Tracked and reported status & other metrics against goals on an ongoing basis and ensured task completion on time; managed a team in offshore location

Environment: C#, .NET 2.0/4.0/4.5/4.5.1/4.5.2, SQL Server 2008/2012, Visual Studio 2012/2013/2015, ASP.NET M/C 4/5, ADO.NET, LINQ, JQUERY, AJAX, XML, HTML5 & CSS 3/4, JavaScript, AngularJS, BootStrap, WCF, Web Services/Web API, SOAP, IIS 7.0, Windows 2007/2008, GIT Bitbucket & GIT SVN, JIRA Board

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electrical) from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (JNTU) in 2011

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
C#, VB .Net, UNIX, XML		
SQL/T-SQL, PL/SQL, Angular JS/8		
ASP.NET framework		
WebServices, Web API		
HTML/CSS, BOOTSTRAP, JavaScript		
jQuery, XHTML, XML, XSL, XSLT		
MS Visio, InstallShield		
Entity Framework, SQL Server		
MS Visual Studio .net		
Visual Code, Data Stream, SQL Management		

Jira Board, Confluence Pages	
Tortoise SVN, GIT Bitbucket, TFS	
HTTP, HTTPS, TCP/IP, UDP/IP and FTP	
IIS	

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Telugu				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.